Santiago Bustamante Garcia

+57 (300) 729 6896 busta117@gmail.com skype: sbusta117 www.santiagobustamante.info

SUMMARY

I'm an engineer who love the new technologies with several years of experience developing native iOS games and applications both in academic and professional projects. I have experience developing REST APIs for communicate the client and the server. I have participated in multiple projects which gave me great experience personally and professionally working both my myself and in a team.

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer, Periferia IT

Bogotá, Cundinamarca — apr 2013 - current

I'm a member of the iOS developers team

iOS Developer, KOGI Mobile

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2013 - apr 2014

I'm a member of the iOS developers team, in this job i'm in charge of VarCity app(https://itun.es/i6Fk2vj) and another app currently on development. Also i participate in the development of Ground Miles by Bupa (https://itun.es/i6Fp2Q6), UNE MAS (https://itun.es/i6Fp5hj), phase 2 of PureGym app (https://itun.es/i6Fz6yV), iOS app for TP Orthodontics (https://www.tportho.com/ still on development), and iOS version of Beats Medical app (http://www.beatsmedical.com/ still on development) , iOS app for Coordinadora (http://www.coordinadora.com/ still on development)

iOS Developer, GARA Entertainment

Medellín, Antioquia — dec 2011 - jun 2013

I developed several games using Objective-C and frameworks such as cocos2D, box2D and Unity. I developed native iOS apps and theirs backend in php and WCF. In this job I was in charge of the development of Oh My Nuts!

Game(https://itun.es/i6Fk25f), their free version
(https://itun.es/i6F27C2) and two other games that are not in the AppStore yet, GoBo(http://youtu.be/nGUnDZoJ_NE) and StreetRep (http://youtu.be/LWIAKDe26OM); also i developed the ipad version for a colombian retail named ÉXITO (https://itun.es/i6Fk3H9)

iOS Developer, Doctus LTDA

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2011 - dec 2011

I developed some frameworks for use in house, also started the development of several iOS games.

iOS Developer, Freelance

I developed some iOS native apps for external clients, some of these applications still alive in the AppStore with the following links:

<u>https://itun.es/i6FV2yH</u> (internet radio station, Medellin Hip Hop)
<u>https://itun.es/i6Fk3H3</u> (sushi restaurant in Medellin-Colombia,
Sushi Market)

https://itun.es/i6Fk25x (events list for ANDI)

social network using GPS called MNU, this app is not alive

TUAPP Contest 2013

I participated in the University Apps Contest powered by Cursor in Santiago de Chile, in this contest we're finalists with an application that suggests another way of tourism using quests (http://www.seekit.info/).

EDUCATION

EAFIT University (Medellin - Colombia)

System Engineering — 2007-2013

SKILLS

- Objective-C and iOS development for iOS 4.3 and above
- Java.
- PHP.
- MySQL.
- Xcode.
- Memory management and debugging for iOS apps using instruments.
- Cocos2D, Box2D and Unity frameworks for mobile game developing.
- C#

- WCF for REST API
- Adobe products (photoshop, illustrator, flash, premiere)